

# CHITU CATALIN GEORGE

Freelancer: Content Creator/Partner (Project based) - Teespring, Inc,

Redbubble Ltd., Maker Studios Inc., Google Inc., YouTube LLC.,

BroadbandTV Corp.

From Bucharest, Romania

# **Contact details**

Email: catalin.george.chitu@gmail.com Tel: +40760730617

## About me

With the help of a set of skills very well outlined in the areas of data analysis and automation and with experience working in the financial-accounting field, they can help companies in analyzing, identifying and meeting financial objectives.

# **Professional experience**

Experience by departments

Graphics / Web design / DTP: 6 years and 8 months

Quality Control: 3 months

Finance / Accounting: 3 years and 4 months

Feb 2015 - present 6 years and 9 months Freelancer: Content Creator/Partner (Project based) - Teespring, Inc, Redbubble Ltd.,

Maker Studios Inc., Google Inc., YouTube LLC., BroadbandTV Corp.

Remote (from home) | Graphics / Web design / DTP | Media / Internet

- -Creating audio-video material for educational purposes for subscribers to global social networks
- -Creating designs and selling clothes on various online platforms

## Acquired skills and knowledge:

Adobe Premiere, Sony Vegas, - Photoshop

Nov 2019 - Jun 2020

## Financial Analyst - ELEFANT ONLINE SA

8 months

Bucharest | Finance / Accounting | Commerce / Retail

Identification, analysis and reporting to Management and shareholders of the following financial statements:

- -Analysis of sales, purchases and stocks by budget group and cost centers
- -Identifying internal or external frauds
- -Analyzing returns and items and customers with high probability of return rate
- -Verification of vouchers and related orders
- -Identifying / reconciling substantial differences between payroll and accounting, etc.
- -Checking the advances offered to employees
- -Analysis of marketing costs (sms, ads, affiliates, retargeting, radio / tv, flyers, etc.)
- -Analysis of stock movements, stock age, stock rotation (inventory days, slow moving, aging, etc.)
- -Verification of the correct evaluation / unloading of stocks in accounting
- -Analysis of packaging costs and packaging stock
- -Analysis of delivery costs (to customers / to work points)
- -Identifying returns to suppliers
- -Analysis of additional discounts from suppliers (reaching the margin established with a discount from the supplier, etc.)
- -Identifying stocks and liquidity at work points
- -Checking the age of the balances on suppliers
- -Analysis of damaged stocks (quantitative, value, aging, etc.)
- -Analysis of margin and stocks at supplier level

- -Cost estimates
- -Reconciliation of the value of stocks from operational vs. values from accounting
- -Other checks on OPEX + other ad-hoc reports

## Acquired skills and knowledge:

Outlook, Charisma, ERP, QlikView, Google Chrome, tableau, entersoft business suite, Microsoft Teams

#### Nov 2017 - Nov 2019

#### **Senior Accountant - ELEFANT ONLINE SA**

2 years and 1 month

Bucharest | Finance / Accounting | Commerce / Retail

- -Performing the monthly verifications before drawing up the declarations (verification of inactive suppliers, non-exigible VAT, VAT on collection, VIES, etc.)
- -Preparation and processing of journals and declarations for submission to ANAF: 300, 394, 390, F4109, A4200. etc.
- -Reconciliation of the balance at the end of the month
- -Assisting the ERP development department in implementing the projects requested by the accounting department
- -Documentation and automation of accounting processes (internal through the technical or external department through consulting companies)
- -Automation of monthly reports (creation of macros in MS Excel VBA)
- -Initiating and implementing new procedures and updating outdated work procedures
- -Initialization of junior accountants

## Acquired skills and knowledge:

Outlook, Excel, entersoft, asana

## Apr 2017 - Nov 2017

#### Junior Accountant - ELEFANT ONLINE SA

8 months

Bucharest | Finance / Accounting | Commerce / Retail

- -Checking the conformity of invoices and entering invoices from suppliers in the ERP system
- -Verification of NIR / NRR / invoices
- -Verification and introduction of expense statements in ERP
- -Verification and introduction of service invoices in ERP
- -Verification of transactions from bank statements with ERP account balances
- -Issuing balance confirmations, approving and sending them
- -Verification and generation of revaluations on external suppliers
- -Processing and checking account sheets from suppliers and customers
- -Verification of suppliers with non-exigible VAT, VAT on collection and non-VAT payers
- -Other ad-hoc checks

### Acquired skills and knowledge:

asana. entersoft business suite. - Microsoft Office

# Oct 2015 - Dec 2015

## QA Tester - Electronic Arts Romania SRL

3 months

Bucharest | Quality Control | IT / Telecom

Identifying potential bugs in application development.

Reproducing and reporting them to the company's developers.

Testing the functionality and compatibility of applications on different electronic devices.

## Acquired skills and knowledge:

Android, Jira, iOS, Hansoft, itools, Office

### May 2015 - May 2015

#### Internship - Titan Mar S.A.

1 month

Ilfov | Finance / Accounting | Construction

Assisting in the daily activities undertaken within the company's financial accounting department.

## Acquired skills and knowledge:

microsoft word, Microsot Office

## **Education**

## 2013 - 2016 Bachelor's degree - Universitatea Crestina "Dimitrie Cantemir"

Finante Banci si Contabilitate | Bucharest

After completing the courses specializing in "Accounting and Management Informatics", I obtained the title of Economist.

#### 2008 - 2012 High School / Vocation

High School / Vocational school - Liceul de metrologie "Traian Vuia"

Electronica si automatizari | Bucharest

After completing the courses on computer technical specialization, I obtained the professional qualification:

"Computer technician"

## **Skills**

#### General skills

Adobe Premiere, Microsoft Office, Sony Vegas Pro, E-commerce, Visual Basic for applications, VBA, macros, asana, entersoft business suite, Charisma, tableau software, Qlik View, Hansoft, Java, intellij

# Foreign languages

english - Advanced, romanian - Advanced

# Other info

#### Conferences

Tax & Finance Forum

period Nov 2018 - Nov 2018

Participation in the events within the Tax & Finance Forum, where the most important legislative and fiscal aspects with an impact on the business environment, the main challenges for Romanian taxpayers and solutions for adapting to the new provisions were addressed. They were presented and analyzed, together with experts from the most important consulting companies, trends and fiscal policies at international level, the harmonization of Romanian legislation, the main amendments and regulations of the Fiscal Code and the Fiscal Procedure Code.

## **Prizes and Distinctions**

Best Employee elefant.ro

acquired on Jan 2018

## **Driving license**

Category: B / attained: 02 Nov 2011